Willie Wu

Senior Software Engineer

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in developing in high-paced and ambiguous environments. Led teams of 4 or more developers to deliver projects and features on schedule while driving code improvements across organizations of ~200 developers. Accustomed to working with cross functional partners (program management, executive leadership, designers) to deliver value.

Contact Information

Phone: 858.205.3438 | Location: Sunnyvale, CA 94085

Email: willie.wu17@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/williewu17/

Skills

• Programming Languages: Python | Java | JavaScript | SQL | C++ | Swift

• Databases: Postgres | DynamoDB

• Frameworks: FastAPI | Flask | Spring Boot | React

• Other: REST | git | Docker | Terraform | ML

Work Experience

Rivian, Palo Alto | Senior Software Engineer | 02/2021 - Present

- Developed a web application using Javascript and React, providing insights into the performance of the software organization, enabling teams to make data-driven decisions on software priorities
- Designed and implemented a software quality report ingestion tool using AWS Lambda, managed through Terraform that improved quality by 15% by delivering real time metrics to developers.
- Consolidated Java Spring boot, and Python backend services to improve data sharing and efficiency for software package management and reduce organizational overhead by 50%
- Participated as primary fallback for on-call system for the team, assisting stakeholders using team tools and answering questions maintaining our team's 99% uptime.
- Created from the ground up a full backend tech stack using Python, FastAPI, Terraform and AWS Serverless resources built to track critical organizational data with emphasis on future scalability
- Mentored other engineers, uplifting overall technical skills of the team by hosting lunch-and-learns and improving team documentation and practices

Amazon, Seattle | Software Development Engineer Intern | 06/2020 - 09/2020

- Designed and deployed a high-throughput Java service within Amazon Web Services to automate engineering team workflows, leading to an estimated ~300 hours of engineering work saved per month
- Built automation scripts to search for log errors to decrease on-call turnaround time by 25%

Apple, Cupertino | Engineering Intern | 03/2019 - 09/2019

- Utilized data analysis tools in Python to interpret physiological data from user studies
- Presented key research findings to cross-disciplinary teams for future design and feature considerations
- Streamlined workflows to improve team efficiency by 50% through automation scripts, allowing higher speed of data collection

Education

Masters in computer science, 2020 | University of California Los Angeles Bachelors in Bioengineering, 2019 | University of California Los Angeles Cum Laude, UC Regents Scholar, Dean's Honor List

Accolades and Certifications

- Research Publication: Deep learning and radiomics: the utility of Google TensorFlow™ Inception in classifying clear cell renal cell carcinoma and oncocytoma on multiphasic CT (June 2019)
- 2020 | Architecture and Systems Engineering: Models and Methods to Manage Complex Systems | MIT